Guide to Montana Historical Society. Research Historian records 1979-2006
Montana Historical Society
- Subject Files
  - Press Committee, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 6 / 30-32)
  - "Quarries of Last Chance Gulch" (chronological list of articles), 1994-2000 (Box-folder 6 / 33)
  - Railroad (includes sketch maps from Encyclopedia of Western Railroads ), undated (Box-folder 6 / 34)
  - Jeannette Rankin (includes bibliographies), undated (Box-folder 6 / 35-36)
  - Ginger Renner, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 6 / 37)
  - Research Historian position, 1993-2000 (Box-folder 6 / 38)
  - Research Historian tasks (quarterly reports), 1993-2006 (Box-folder 6 / 39)
  - Roosevelt Arch centennial, 2003 (Box-folder 6 / 40)
  - Lee Rostad, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 6 / 41)
  - Mary Ann Rotondi (re Jeannette Rankin, Rebecca Felton, Nellie Ross), 1993 (Box-folder 6 / 42)
  - Charles M. Russell artwork and prints, undated (Box-folder 6 / 43)
  - Charles M. Russell Center at Montana Historical Society (proposal), 1996 (Box-folder 6 / 44)
  - Sacred Heart Cemetery, Helena (re relocation of graves and missing headstones; also includes list of burials), 1999 (Box-folder 6 / 45)
  - Robert A. Saindon (re Meriwether Lewis' "Unhappy Affair" on Marias River), 1999-2005 (Box-folder 6 / 46)
  - Saint Peter's Episcopal Church, Helena (includes chronology and WPA list of records), undated (Box-folder 6 / 47)
  - Salute to Schools, 1989 (Box-folder 6 / 48)
  - Sanborn maps (includes how-to guide and list of MHS Library Sanborn maps), undated (Box-folder 6 / 49)
  - Robert Scriver, 2000 (Box-folder 6 / 50)
  - Bill Sharp (re Civilian Conservation Corps and Fort Missoula (includes many clippings), undated (Box-folder 6 / 51)
  - Sheep, undated (Box-folder 6 / 52)
  - State symbols, undated (Box-folder 6 / 53)
  - State Historic Preservation Office (SHPO: includes how to research historic buildings, National Register forms, etc.), undated (Box-folder 7 / 1)
  - State Trails Plan Advisory Committee, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 7 / 2)
  - Wallace Stegner, 1972-1993 (Box-folder 7 / 3)
  - Student handbook, 2002 (Box-folder 7 / 4)
  - Summary of years' events (clippings), 1898-1902 (Box-folder 7 / 5)
  - Teachers' Advisory Panel, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7 / 6)
  - Teaching history (includes "Montana Standards for Social Studies"), 2000 (Box-folder 7 / 7)
  - "Thinking Through American History" (Golden Triangle Curriculum Consortium), 2001-2005 (Box-folder 7 / 8-11)
  - Johnnie Thomas biographical sketch and correspondence (African American woman from Miles City), 2001-2004 (Box-folder 7 / 12)
  - Al Thompson (includes "Riding Alongside: Joseph H. Proctor and the FUF Ranch" re African American cowboys), 1997 (Box-folder 7 / 13)
  - K. Ross Toole memoriam, 1981 (Box-folder 7 / 14)
  - Travel Montana webpage editing, 1997 (Box-folder 7 / 15)
  - Tri-State History Consortium (includes MSU Northern grant), 2001-2003 (Box-folder 7 / 16)
  - Trustees (includes member biographies), 2000 (Box-folder 7 / 17)
  - Trustees Awards (includes lists and announcements), 1978-2004 (Box-folder 7 / 18)
  - Trustees Awards (includes nominations), 1998-2000 (Box-folder 7 / 19)
  - Trustees Awards (includes Trustees Award, Educators Award and biographical information about the recipients), 1987, 1994-2006 (Box-folder 7 / 20-28)
  - U. S. Congressmen lists and papers, undated (Box-folder 7 / 29)
  - U. S. Forest Service directories, 1978-1991 (Box-folder 7 / 30)
  - University of Montana (includes list of history theses and dissertations), 1982 (Box-folder 7 / 31)
  - Vigilantes (re Henry Plummer controversy), 1997-1999 (Box-folder 7 / 32)
  - Virginia City (includes Mona Vanek's "Bullets"), 1994-1997 (Box-folder 7 / 33)
  - Virginia City (includes inventory and history of buildings by John Ellingson)), 1994 (Box-folder 7 / 34)
  - Virginia City (includes photocopies of photographs), undated (Box-folder 7 / 35)
  - Virginia City / Nevada City Preservation Task Force (includes report to Governor, minutes, and attachments), 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7 / 36-37)
  - Virginia City Special Resource Study environmental Assessment, 1995 (Box-folder 7 / 38)
  - Visitor survey by Steve McCool, 1993 (Box-folder 7 / 39)
  - "Visual history of Montana", 2000 (Box-folder 7 / 40)
  - Thomas J. Walsh bio-bibliography, 1998 (Box-folder 7 / 41)
  - Dennis and Phyllis Washington Foundation (re grant for Montana History Conference student sessions; essay contest), 1999-2006 (Box-folder 7 / 42-43)
  - Webpages: Montana history, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7 / 44)
  - Webpages: MT Kids (re Montana history), 1997-2002 (Box-folder 7 / 45)
  - Western Writers of America, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 7 / 46)
  - Pat Williams (re his KUFM program "Speaking of that"), 2000-2002 (Box-folder 7 / 47)
  - Works Progress Administration (WPA) records (includes inventory to collection at Montana State University), 1987-1996, undated (Box-folder 7 / 48)
  - World's fairs (includes chronological lists of fairs), 1851-2005 (Box-folder 7 / 49)
- Speeches and Writings
  - Talks by Dave Walter (includes "Looking Backward at Looking Forward", untitled talk re Montana Heritage Project), 1999 (Box-folder 7 / 50)
  - Student papers (includes "Silver City" by Sara Levitan; "Custer's Crow Scouts" by Peri Dawn Bauerle) [permission required for publication use], 1975, 1996 (Box-folder 7 / 51)
- Miscellany
  - List of published material transferred to the Library, 2007 (Box-folder 7 / 52)
  - List of electronic records files, 1997-2006 (Box-folder 7 / 53)